itcentralstation.com 2019-04-30

# Privacy and Cookies Policy | IT Central Station

**IT Central Station Privacy And Cookies Policy**

This Privacy and Cookies Policy was last updated on January 20, 2019.

**I. Overview**

IT Central Station Ltd. (“ **IT Central Station** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **our** ”, or “ **us** ”) takes the privacy and protection of personal information seriously. By visiting our Site, registering as a Member, or using the Services, you acknowledge and accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy and Cookies Policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”). Unless otherwise defined herein, capitalized terms shall have the meanings assigned to such terms in the IT Central Station Terms of Use, which can be found here and which incorporate this Privacy Policy by reference. This Privacy Policy describes IT Central Station's practices with respect to Personal Information that we collect when you visit our Site or use the Services. 

“ **Personal Information** ” is information that is personally identifiable such as names, addresses, e-mail addresses, or phone numbers, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing. In some regions, an individuals’ internet protocol address (“ **IP address** ”) may be considered Personal Information. We collect and use Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy from visitors to our Site and Users of our Services. 

IT Central Station complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. IT Central Station has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

IT Central Station is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. IT Central Station may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

IT Central Station is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and for the subsequent transfers of such personal data to any third party acting as an agent on IT Central Stations’s behalf. IT Central Station will be liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless IT Central Station proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

Under certain conditions, as more fully described on the Privacy Shield website on [this page](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

BY VISITING OUR SITE, USING THE SERVICES, OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION THROUGH THE SERVICES, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING AND USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, INCLUDING THE COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE, STORAGE, TRANSFER AND PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AS DESCRIBED HEREIN. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS IN OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY. 

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE OUR SITE OR BECOME A REGISTERED MEMBER.**

**II. Personal Information We Collect**

IT Central Station is committed to data minimization. As such, we collect only the information which is necessary to facilitate the purposes and uses reflected in this Privacy Policy.

Depending on how you interact with IT Central Station, the Personal Information we collect from you may vary. For example, to create an account we may ask only for a company email address. In other circumstances, such as when you complete a form related to a particular service offering, we may ask you to provide other information, which may include your name, phone number, job title, and/or employer name. After registering, you may provide us with additional information about your employment and professional experience. If you register with our LinkedIn™ log-in mechanism, we may collect your LinkedIn profile picture. We may also collect other information as indicated in the LinkedIn log-in screen during the registration process and as detailed in this Privacy Policy. 

When you contribute posts and reviews, participate in our surveys (either directly, or through third party service providers), or provide any other Content to the Services through other means, we will collect all the information you provide. If you exchange messages with others through the Site, we may store these messages to deliver them and to allow you to manage them. 

Please be aware that while some pieces of information that you provide to us would not be sufficient to identify you when seen by another User without any context, the combination of different pieces of information that you provide for viewing by other Users, or any contextual information, may allow other Users to identify you. 

When you contact us by sending us an e-mail or when you use any of our contact forms, we will collect any information that is contained in (and/or attached to) your e-mail or text message, or that you enter into such forms. 

**III. Personal Information Collected Via Technology**

When you visit our Site or use our Services, your device is automatically providing information to us to enable us to respond and customize our response to you. The type of information we collect by automated means may vary, but generally includes technical information about your computer, such as your IP address or other device identifier. The information we collect also may include usage information and statistics about your interaction with IT Central Station. That information may include the URLs of our web pages that you visit, URLs of referring and exiting pages, page views, time spent on a page, number of clicks, platform type, location data, and other information about how you used our Site. We collect this information to help us provide a customized experience. We may display this information so that Users can learn more about other Users. We do not currently respond to 'do not track' signals and similar settings or mechanisms. 

Automated means of data collection include the following:

  * **Web Browser.** When you visit an IT Central Station website, your browser automatically sends us your Internet protocol ("IP") address so that the web pages you request can be sent to your computer or device. We use your IP address to determine additional information, such as your employer name, whether the computer or device has ever been used to visit IT Central Station before, which IT Central Station features were used the most often, and how much time was spent on a page. 

  * **Web Beacons and Log Files.** We use "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags, tracking pixels, and clear GIFs) on our Site. These web beacons allow us and third parties to collect information such as the IP address of the device, the URL of the web page, the time the page was viewed, the type of browser used, and any additional information in cookies that may have been set by the third party. The information is typically collected in log files, which generally track traffic on our Site. The information is used for analytical purposes and to manage technical issues that may arise. We do not attempt to identify individual users through this information. 

  * **Location Data.** We may determine your location from your device's IP address or from the URLs we receive. 

  * **Cookies.** We also collect information using cookies to help us identify you when you visit our Site, and we may share cookies with third-party advertisers or advertising networks to provide you with relevant, targeted ads. For more information on cookies and similar tracking mechanisms, how we use them, and how you can control them, please see the next section below entitled “Cookies Policy and Ad Choices”. 

**IV. Cookie Policy and Ad Choices**

IT Central Station stores a small text file called a “Cookie” on your computer to store your login information (if any) and your personal preferences for the Services. IT Central Station may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). While you will still be able to use the Services if you disable Cookies in your browser, certain parts of the Services may not function as effectively. After you register and enable Cookies, we may associate this information with Personal Information that we have collected from you. 

We work with third parties, such as Google and Facebook, to provide analytics services that may use the Cookies set on your device to provide advertisements, measure the performance of advertising, and track traffic to IT Central Station generally. In addition, we have implemented [Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en), which categorizes cookie information so that we and third-party service providers may better deliver content and/or advertisements that are relevant and useful to you on our Site and various websites across the internet. You may opt out of tracking by Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting services by visiting [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated) or by downloading the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). If you do not want Facebook to use information based on your IT Central Station activity for the purpose of showing you ads, you may opt out [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217). 

You may also be able to disable placement of some (but not all) Cookies by setting your browser to decline cookies, though this may degrade your user experience. Additionally, if you change computers or web browsers, you will need to opt out again. A useful resource for information about deleting and controlling cookies can be found at [AboutCookies.org.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) Although our Site does not currently respond to 'do not track' browser headers, you can limit tracking through these third-party programs and by taking the other steps discussed above. 

**V. Use of Information We Collect**

In general, information (including Personal Information) you submit to us, or to third parties that support us in collecting information, as well as information we collect about you via technology, are used by us to provide you and other Users with the Services, to respond to requests that you make, to improve our Services, and to operate, maintain, and improve the features, functionality, performance, and support of the Services. We may share your username, employer company size, employer industry, job title, photo, and browsing behavior with other Users. We do not display your email address or phone number on the Site. We do not reveal your company name to other Users unless you visit the My Profile page and choose to display it. 

We may also use your Personal Information to provide you with notifications related to your use of the Services, such as electronic newsletters or promotional e-mails. 

We use cookies and log file information to (a) collect or store personal information; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the use of our Site; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors; (e) track your use of our Site; and (f) customize advertisements on our Site and retargeting advertisements on third party websites. 

To use certain services on our Site, such as downloading reports, you may be asked to provide Personal Information (e.g. your name, email address, employer name, or phone number). We may share your company size, employer name, browsing behavior, and other information we collect about you with our partners, sponsors, and advertisers (“ **Partners** ”). See our list of Partners [here](http://go.itcentralstation.com/sponsors-partners/). 

**By sharing your information with us, you agree that (a) IT Central Station may share your name, email address, phone number, and job title with its Partners, and (b) IT Central Station and its Partners may contact you by way of email, telephone, mail, or other means of communication to provide you with access to Content, surveys, direct marketing, and promotional materials in connection with your activity on the Site.**

If you do not want this information shared, you may opt out of our sharing this information with our Partners by contacting us at the email address set forth in the section entitled “Opting Out” below. In addition, you may contact a Partner directly if you have any questions about such Partner’s use of your information or if you would like to cease receiving communications from a specific Partner. 

Our website includes social media features such as the "Share This" button for Twitter and LinkedIn. These features may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with each of these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the feature. 

**VI. Our Partners and Other Websites**

Our Partners may include tracking technologies (e.g. cookies or web beacons) within pages on our Site. This is in order for our Partners to set and read their own cookies when you browse information about their companies. These tracking technologies are not subject to the control of IT Central Station. 

Similarly, our Services may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by IT Central Station. The provision of such links is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such websites or their location or their content. We have no control over, do not review, and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to any outside websites. 

**VII. Public Postings**

One of the purposes of the Services is for Members to share product- and vendor-related information with other Users. Therefore, you should assume that any information that you post, including any Personal Information you may choose to provide (but excluding your email address and phone number), will be made available to other Users of the Services. If you post Content on our site (e.g. product review, question, answer, etc.), such Content may be made available on third party websites and may be included within materials distributed by our Partners, but such Content will not include your email address, phone number, full name, or employer name. We may provide you with the ability to anonymously post certain comments, in which case we will not include your contact information (i.e., name, username, email address, or your employer) on the Site in connection with such comments. However, you should know that our internal records may associate your contact information with such comments. 

**VIII. Legal Basis for the Processing of Personal Information**

IT Central Station relies on both consent and legitimate business interests for processing Personal Information. 

For example, IT Central Station may process Personal Information with a User’s consent when a User agrees that we may process information that the User inputs into our Site or that we collect via our Site. 

On other occasions, even in the absence of explicit consent, IT Central Station may process Personal Information pursuant to specific purposes which further our legitimate interests, provided that our legitimate interests are not overridden by the User’s reasonable expectations of privacy. For example, IT Central Station may process Personal Information pursuant to legitimate business purposes to respond to User inquiries, to fulfill User requests, to send Users relevant marketing information and offers, to provide Users with more relevant ads and content, to complete transactions, to provide customer service, to send administrative information, and to personalize Users’ experiences with the Site. 

In addition, IT Central Station may process Personal Information where IT Central Station is required by law to do so. 

**IX. Feedback**

If you provide feedback about the Services to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. We will collect all information contained in such feedback and treat the Personal Information in it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**X. Disclosure of Personal Information to Service Providers**

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose to or share your Personal Information (e.g. full name, e-mail address, or phone number) with third parties, unless you ask or authorize us to do so. 

In addition to providing your Personal Information to our Partners, we provide your Personal Information to third party service providers and suppliers who work on our behalf or with us to provide you with some of the services and features of the Services and to help us communicate with our Users (“ **Service Providers** ”). Our Service Providers, however, do not have any independent right to use your Personal Information for their own purposes not connected to IT Central Station. IT Central Station will always attempt to limit the information we provide to what is reasonably sufficient for our Service Partners to carry out their responsibilities to IT Central Station. 

We may share some or all of your Personal Information with any parent company, subsidiary, joint venture, or other company under common control (collectively, “ **Affiliates** ”), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. 

In the event IT Central Station goes through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of IT Central Station or its assets may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

We may (and you authorize us to) disclose information we have collected from and about you (including Personal Information) if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us; (b) enforce our IT Central Station Terms of Use and Privacy Policy; or (c) protect and defend our rights or property, or the rights and property of the users of our Services or third parties. 

**XI. Opting Out**

If you wish to exercise any of your rights in relation to your Personal Information, including exercising your opt-out rights, please send us an email to [privacy@itcentralstation.com](mailto:privacy@itcentralstation.com). 

You may access, modify, or delete your Personal Information by logging into the service and visiting the My Profile page. 

We may send newsletters or promotional communications to our users. To unsubscribe to these communications, you will be required to click an "Unsubscribe" link in these emails and confirm the email address for which you would like to unsubscribe. 

We may send you service-related announcements (such as, but not limited to, a notice that we have changed our Services or our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy) when we believe it is necessary to do so. 

You may request that your Account be terminated and that your Personal Information be deleted by sending an email to [privacy@itcentralstation.com](mailto:privacy@itcentralstation.com). Any termination of your account may involve deletion of your Account information from our live databases and all the information and data stored for such Account in the Services. IT Central Station will not have any liability whatsoever to you for any termination of your Account or the related deletion of your information. 

You may request a copy of the Personal Information we store about you by sending an email to [privacy@itcentralstation.com](mailto:privacy@itcentralstation.com). You may also request that IT Central Station transfer your information or provide you with copies of your information to enable the transfer of your information to a third party. 

When we delete Personal Information that we have collected from or about you, it will be deleted from our active databases but may remain in our archives. Although IT Central Station may deactivate a User’s registration pursuant to their request, it may continue to retain the User’s information for legitimate business purposes as set forth above. 

We process the Personal Information of potential Partners for certain legitimate business purposes related to their request to receive information about our business-to-business services or to schedule a demonstration of our online, media, marketing, or data services products or programs. In the event that potential Partners do not wish to receive further marketing or sales emails from IT Central Station, they may opt-out of receiving additional emails by way of following the unsubscribe mechanism provided at the bottom of emails sent by IT Central Station. 

**XII. Privacy of Minors**

Our Site and Services are directed to professionals. If you are not 18 or older, you are not authorized to use the Services. We do not intentionally collect or maintain information in the Services from those visitors and Users of the Services who are under 13 years old. If you learn that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without consent, please contact us. 

**XIII. California Privacy Rights**

California law permits California residents to request certain details about how a business shares their Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes. In addition, if you are a California resident, you may ask us to refrain from sharing your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you have any questions regarding our compliance with California privacy law, please contact us at the email address set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below. 

**XIV. Data Retention**

IT Central Station will retain the Personal Information that you provide while your membership is in existence or as needed to provide you with services. We may retain your Personal Information after you have cancelled your membership if retention is reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to meet regulatory requirements, to resolve disputes between our Users, to prevent fraud and abuse, or to enforce this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. We may also retain Personal Information, for a limited period of time, if requested by law enforcement. 

**XV. Security and Confidentiality**

IT Central Station has put in place commercially reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. However, no company, including IT Central Station, can fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information. IT Central Station has implemented technical, organizational and administrative measures which are generally accepted by the industry to protect the Personal Information in its possession. These measures include, but are not limited to, the implementation of current security technologies and processes to protect your information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. In particular, our security systems include authenticated access to internal databases, audits of processes and procedures, reviews of overall web security, and the use of restrictions of access to Personal Information in our possession. Additionally, we use encryption (e.g. HTTPS) to protect data transmitted to and from our Site. 

**XVI. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

As part of the IT Central Station Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy is subject to occasional amendment, in accordance with the terms of the IT Central Station Terms of Use. 

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will update at the top of this Privacy Policy the date upon which the modified policy became effective, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we may disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Your continued use of the Site or our Services shall constitute your acceptance of the modified Privacy Policy. 

**XVII. Contact Us**

This Privacy Policy was drafted with transparency in mind but it does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of our collection and use of Personal Information. We are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our collection or use of your Personal Information or regarding our Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@itcentralstation.com](mailto:privacy@itcentralstation.com). 

IT Central Station  
Phone: +1 (646) 328-1944  
Mailing address: IT Central Station, 55 Nahal Sorek, Modiin, Israel  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  
Email: [privacy@itcentralstation.com](mailto:privacy@itcentralstation.com)
